Hello?
Please.
I just need to get to town.
Please?
- Hyah, hyah!
Fucker.
Hello?
Is someone there?
No, no!
-Abraham.
Welcome home.
-Hello, Mina.
-Look at all this dust.
-How are you feeling?
-I've had worse days.
Sit.
I'll make you a cold drink.
Rudy...
come prepare the table
for dinner.
-Coming.
- Max.
-Yes?
-May I speak with you?
Do you trust me, Max?
-You're my father.
-I have made
a disturbing discovery.
Perhaps it was foolish of me
to think
that we could hide away forever.
I have known for a long time...
that it might come...
and we would be ready if it did.
But I'm going to need your help
and cooperation.
-Of course.
-You're a good boy, Max.
-Not again.
Not again. Please.
Damn work.
Sometimes I don't know
if all this is for us...
or for his bloody crusade.
No.
Mustn't question him.
Mustn't.
Leave me alone!
The devil is coming,
and I want to be ready for him.
-You're not making any sense.
You need to rest.
-You're right.
Of course.
I did not think
I would have sons.
I always wanted a daughter.
Softer.
More difficult to keep safe.
-You see them?
Mapping for the new
railroad extension.
After them, more will follow.
Do you remember Amsterdam, Max?
-Only a little.
-Or London before that?
-No.
-You were too young, I think.
Just as well.
It was a filthy, stinking place.
I'm sure you've noticed
your mother has been acting...
strange lately.
Years ago,
your mother and her friends
called on me...
to fight off...
a terrible threat that had
followed them to London.
She was attacked by the enemy,
and her blood was infected.
This experience
changed your mother.
These memories
she carries with her
are her scars
that will never heal.
So we came to California
to build our family.
-♪ You're like a sweetheart... ♪
And California
has been good to us.
-♪ From ocean to ocean ♪
♪ For you my devotion ♪
-But now I suspect
that same threat has followed us
from the old world to the new.
I am fearful
for your mother's well-being
and all of our souls.
-♪ ...mother's knee ♪
-These creatures
have a connection
to your mother's mind.
If they are near,
they may be drawn to her.
I need you
to help me protect her,
watch over her.
A year ago...
there were no railroad tracks
anywhere
in this part of the state.
Barely a town to speak of.
The world is getting smaller...
closing in on us.
And as the new world
grows more populous,
they follow.
Like rats...
with a merchant vessel.
-Are you Dr. Van Helsing?
-Yeah.
-Please. There was an accident
on our worksite.
My brother's been injured.
-He was caught
under heavy equipment.
We need your help.
-Please. We can pay.
Come on, come on.
-Lay him flat.
My son will help you.
I'll gather my things.
Show them to barn.
-Move the tarpaulin
over the hay.
-Okay. Get back here.
-Gentle.
Okay.
-Good.
-Mm-hmm. Good.
-Elsie.
-Mm-hmm. It's okay.
Okay.
-What is this man's name?
-Edward. Eddie.
-Edward, you can hear me, yes?
-Mm.
-Okay.
-The lung has been punctured
by a broken rib.
Tension pneumothorax
has already begun.
We need to relieve the pressure.
Hold him still.
-Mm-hmm.
-You'll be okay.
- Aah.
-Okay. Okay.
Okay. Yup.
Shh!
-Elsie.
-Yes. Shh, shh, shh, shh!
Relax, okay?
You're okay.
-It's important
to keep the tube in place
so that the pressure
will not build back up again.
-Thank you.
-You'll want to take him
to the hospital now in town.
It's only a few miles' journey
from here.
Make sure that the tube
does not become dislodged.
-Thank you.
I thought the worst.
-I only serve God's purpose.
It was not his time.
-Clean your hands.
Don't ruin your appetite.
What are you making?
-Blood pudding.
An old countryside recipe.
It's been a long time
since I've made it.
Usually with pig's blood.
But this...
is your father's own elixir.
Perfected over time.
To cure ailments,
prevent future infection.
How did it get inside?
Take it outside, Max.
Careful.
Those things carry disease.
Turn off that light.
-Max...
Do you believe
in father's creatures?
Have you seen one?
Do you think we're in danger?
It doesn't matter what I think.
Anyway, according to him,
they can't enter uninvited.
-But what
if they're already inside?
-What do you mean?
I've heard something.
At night.
Crying.
And scratching.
Haven't you heard it?
Like an animal, sort of.
And it's not a coyote or a fox
or whatever you're going to say.
-If you don't stop talking, I'm
going to smother you to death
with your own pillow.
Then you won't have anything
to worry about anymore.
-Oh.
-Mrs. Van Helsing.
I'm Elsie.
-Yes, hello.
You were with the injured boy
yesterday.
How is he?
-My brother. Uh, he will --
he'll be fine.
I wanted to say thank you.
I bought these cookies in town.
They're made in San Francisco.
Apparently, they're very good.
-Thank you.
I'm glad you were able
to find us in time.
-One of the workers in town said
a doctor lived in these hills.
I'm in your debt.
My brother...
he's all that I have
in the world.
-Hmm.
To have family is a blessing.
-I agree.
Well, thank you.
-Do you live with
those railroad men?
In that camp?
-I do.
-You're very confident
for a young woman, aren't you?
Sort of...
hard around the edges.
I'm sorry,
that was rude of me to say.
-No need to apologize.
Thank you again
and enjoy the cookies.
-Be careful.
There are hungry things
in the night.
-Uh, I will.
Goodbye, Mrs. Van Helsing.
-It's simple for schoolchildren
half your age.
I don't understand
why you struggle with this.
Let me see.
"What are the four ways
of solving a one-step equation?
-Addition.
S-Subtraction.
Multiplication. Division.
-Good.
What is the first step
of solving a two-step
algebraic equation?
This one, for example.
I will...
I will isolate...
the --
It is clear to me when
you are not applying yourself.
At least when Rudolph
disobeys me, it's deliberate.
But you disobey me in a stupor.
Then you can't understand
why I'm disappointed with you.
-Abraham!
I will be in my study.
Do not disturb me.
-I'll bring some warm milk
to improve our mood.
-Can you try not to be
so stupid all the time?
You know it makes him mad.
-Don't call me stupid.
-I'm sorry
that he's so hard on you.
But you must remember,
his only aim is to keep us safe.
-I know that.
-I suppose I should be grateful,
at least that you are strong.
But still...
I hope
you'll never face our enemy.
Abraham and I
are the only ones left
who really saw him.
The others never saw
his true face.
He held me so close.
I could feel his...
...cold breath on my cheek.
So strange to have cold breath.
Long, white limbs.
White teeth.
And a terrible,
thin, soft mouth.
He moved like a ghost.
The others never saw him.
I did.
I remember.
Your father saved me.
-Rudy.
-I heard voices out there.
You hear them?
-I don't hear anything.
-Tell me what's going on.
-Nothin'.
It's getting dark.
Come inside.
- Max.
Are you asleep?
-We're not safe here.
-What's wrong?
-Listen to me.
We're not safe here.
-We're okay. It's okay.
-No.
-We're alright.
Let's go inside, okay?
Let's go inside.
- Mother.
Mother!
- Come in.
Put that down. Come here.
I'm thirsty.
Abraham.
Max.
My love.
Come closer.
-Do not approach your mother.
Not for your own living soul
and hers.
Sit down. I need your help.
Your mother is a victim
of an unholy illness.
-How could this have happened?
-I've seen this before.
Inflammation that travels
from the blood to the brain.
If we succeed
with the transfusion,
we can bring her back.
She'll never be the same.
I'm pumping air
to create a vacuum.
Now insert the needle
into your arm.
Medicine and healing take time.
You must be patient.
He's here.
-Be calm, my darling.
I can feel him.
I feel his thoughts
penetrating mine.
I see his shadow.
By the window.
He's just outside.
That evil stain.
Those dreadful teeth.
Don't let him take me.
I want to stay here.
I want to stay --
-Be calm. Be calm, my love.
-I want to stay here with you.
How did he find us?
Max, don't. Please.
Don't!
Max!
-Close it! Close it!
Leave.
Leave us now.
-Rudy.
Is everything alright here?
-What do you mean?
-Is it just you?
-And the horse.
Yes.
Alright.
-What's going on?
Is she sick?
-He knows what he's doing.
Don't stay out here too long.
It'll be night soon.
-You must understand
these demons...
can cross great oceans.
They are patient and cunning.
They do not grow old.
And they never die.
-She asleep?
-Yeah.
She needs to rest
to get healthy again.
So don't be loud
and don't bother her.
-When will he be back?
-I don't know.
Whenever he's done working.
Should only be a few hours.
-This isn't bad.
Not as good
as her breakfast, but...
not bad.
Hey!
-Slowpoke!
Rudy! Rudy! Wait!
Shit.
We shouldn't be in here.
You know
we're not allowed in this room.
-Whoops.
We'll just...
throw it away.
-No, he knows where everything
is in his office.
He'll notice it's missing.
-Aren't you curious to know
what he does in here all day?
Hey.
Alright, come on.
Let's clean this up
and get out of here.
-What's that?
-Mother.
Back in Amsterdam.
It's before you were born.
- Turn it off.
Don't.
-There's something under here.
What do you think is down there?
-Close it.
-Did you hear that?
-What was that?!
-Be quiet.
-It's one of father's creatures.
What are you-- Don't.
I just wanna see.
-What are you doing?
-Please.
Help me!
-Don't let it out.
-Shh!
-Help me.
-Step aside.
No. No.
-Rudolf, please stop crying.
It's a miracle
you didn't wake your mother.
She said you were both
too young to see this.
I have protected you
from the truth all these years.
But now...
it seems you have taken
a genuine interest
to my life's work.
Very well.
Come with me.
And we'll finish this lesson.
- Please!
I don't wanna go down there.
Please.
-Everything will be okay.
-In my time, I have killed 13
of the undead by my own hand.
I have trained others in the art
of destroying the undead.
Including your mother's
unfortunate first husband,
Jonathan Harker.
And so therefore,
I am indirectly responsible
for the slaughter of dozens
of their filthy kind.
I had been observing her
for several days.
She was in the process
of changing.
Of leaving behind her humanity
and becoming something...
rotten and unclean.
The undead who found
and fed on her
must have continued
his unholy journey,
because I found no sign of him
except for the imprint
his fangs left behind.
-I wanna go back upstairs.
-Shh.
You need to learn
how to defend yourself
against unholy disease
and unnatural death.
You must...
strike here.
Drive it in to the hilt.
They never go easily.
But do not desist from your work
until you have impaled her
and she no longer struggles
against you.
-No! Max!
-Good.
Good.
To the hilt.
There you have it.
To do offense to the house
of the human spirit
even after
its tenant is gone is...
no easy thing.
-Where were her fangs?
-Ah. They --
They disappear
after the demon dies.
Poof.
And now...
we remove the head.
Rudolph, come.
-I don't want to.
I don't wanna know how.
-I'll do it.
-No.
It is important that he learn.
Rudolph.
Rudolph. Stop this nonsense.
I will help you.
Her neck is brittle.
It won't take long. Stop it.
Rudolph.
-Ow!
-Come!
-Stop!
-Stop it!
-Let him go!
-Go and put some ice
on your face.
Clean up.
Then meet me out on the porch.
I suppose I have never raised
my hand to you before.
Your mother has made me gentle.
Look what you made me do.
-I could leave.
I could take the horse
and ride away.
Disappear.
-Where would you go?
Leave then.
The family will get along fine
without you.
Enough of this.
We are losing light.
This will take some time.
-It will become less difficult
as time passes.
I'm proud of you, son.
- Where have you been?
-Come up to see your mother.
-She looks so sick.
Just like that thing
from the basement.
-We must not abandon hope, son.
Your mother is the strongest
woman I have ever known.
She will recover.
-Abraham.
I was dreaming...
about the night
he came to my room.
Do you remember?
-I will never forget.
-I thought you saved me.
But I was only...
falling deeper into the pit
you pulled me in.
Leave me alone.
-Wait, Rudy.
Listen.
I'm sorry.
-I told you there was
something in the house.
I told you.
And you didn't believe me.
I'm not listening to you
anymore.
You don't know any more
than I do.
-Go ahead.
Anywhere a body can move
from one room to another,
they pass from shadow to shadow.
It's best to do
a self-examination
after contact with the infected.
Thick blood.
Healthy. Good.
Years ago,
my own father...
defined faith
as that which enables us
to believe things
we know to be untrue.
Your faith...
is not misplaced.
Max, come here.
Come and sit.
Yeah.
That bruise has healed well.
Good.
You have grown up, Max.
Somehow, I...
did not see that happen.
And I am sorry.
-Hello?
You're the doctor's son.
-I'm Max.
-Elsie.
You live out here
all alone with your family?
-Yes.
It's just us.
We like it that way.
And you?
- My brother got hired
to survey the railroad
for a new track.
I just --
I'm good with pen and paper.
-You're an artist.
-Uh, maybe.
If I keep working at it.
I draw maps.
One day, they'll use my work
to build something.
I think it would be nice to be
part of building something.
What's wrong?
-My mother is sick.
-I'm sorry.
-This feels different.
And she's not getting better.
Now I wonder...
if my father's treatments
are actually making her worse.
I think sometimes
I must be going crazy.
I'm sorry.
I don't mean to burden you
with our problems.
I understand...
we have to hope for the best.
Oh, God.
-To this woman...
May you receive the Lord's
blessing.
May the Lord bless you
and watch over you.
The Lord make His face to shine
upon you
and be gracious unto you.
The Lord look kindly on you...
and give you peace.
In the name of the Father,
the Son,
and the Holy Spirit.
Amen.
-Amen.
-She was...
a beautiful woman.
-Thank you, Father.
-Woah.
Rudy!
-Go away.
Go away!
I'm not sorry.
Aren't you angry?
-It's just an old guitar.
Rudy...
I'm not mad.
-You said you wanted to leave.
Did you mean it?
-Listen, Rudy.
The things that he does...
It's ugly.
What if we didn't move
to California by choice?
Maybe it was us
being chased out of London,
out of Amsterdam.
Not his decision to leave.
But an exile.
And our family was forced
into isolation because of him.
I can't stay here.
-I don't want to be alone
with him.
-I won't leave you.
I promise I will not leave you.
-I don't believe you.
- Hello?
I-Is this the Van Helsing home?
-It is.
-Ah.
Arthur Holmwood.
I'm an old friend
of your parents.
I haven't seen you
since you were a little baby
on your mother's knee.
She loved you very much,
you know?
Wrote the most beautiful things
about you in her letters.
I pray for her soul every day.
I'm sorry for your loss.
-Thank you.
It's been a hard time
for our family.
-I understand.
You should come back
to London someday.
After all,
your story did start there.
You're always welcome
to my home.
-Is that Arthur Holmwood?
Finally come to visit
his old friend.
Hello, Abraham.
You received my letter?
I did.
It was very kind.
Come inside.
You've had a long journey.
After so many years,
it is good to see your face.
-Likewise, Abraham.
-So, you're living
in Sacramento, then?
-For a little while.
Making my way down to San Diego.
I wanted to see America.
-And how do you find her?
-Large and wild.
Though, I hear
that Union Pacific
is building new tracks this way.
Seems the world is coming
to your doorstep, Doctor.
Much as you may try
to escape it.
I am sorry
to have to offer my condolences.
Mina was...
truly the best of us.
I considered her as a sister,
you know?
-Yes.
You've lost much
over your lifetime, Abraham.
Too much for one man to bear.
But Mina gave you
two strong sons.
And for that, I thank God.
-What do you want, Arthur?
I don't sleep anymore.
And I seek remedy.
Or at least diagnosis.
I-I want...
I want to know
if I am mad or not.
Or more importantly,
if I am a sinner.
-Speak your mind.
-You were like a father to me.
To me and the others.
We would have followed you into
the inferno if you'd asked us.
There was no doubt in our minds
that our task
was holy and righteous.
But I grew up.
I am not the boy
you found all those years ago.
And I know
why you are here in California.
Yes, Abraham.
I know you are continuing
your work.
I've come to ask you to stop.
To put an end to all this.
To let the dead rest.
-No.
What we saw was real.
What I showed you is real.
Evil is real.
But Abraham...
What if we made a mistake?
-No.
No mistakes.
-I wish I could go back in time,
Abraham.
Back to the time before.
I was ready to spend the rest
of my days with Lucy as my wife.
She was to be Lady Godalming.
And I loved her.
And we killed her.
I bled for her
through your tubes and bottles.
And I was ready to give
every last drop if called for.
I was ready to die for her.
And I...
I cut off her head.
Have you nothing to say to me?
-What is it you want?
We did what was needed.
-No.
No, no, you --
you turned me against Lucy.
You -- You filled my mind
with thoughts of demons
and -- and spirits.
You told me she
was already gone.
You told me to be --
to be joyful.
To send her to heaven,
that it was to be by my hand.
The hand she loved best.
That thing was not Lucy.
-Please, Abraham.
Just answer me this.
Am I a murderer?
-Stupid, inbred lord of shit.
You come to my house
to ask me this.
We rid the world of a demon.
King Demon himself.
Do we call it murder
when we kill a wolf
who is at the throat of our cow?
You do not sleep,
because you are weak.
Your kind is always weak.
Pampered, like a spoiled child.
You require a man who works.
A man who knows the feeling
of hot blood in his hands
to come and teach you
how to protect yourself.
Lucy was a monster.
-And what about Mina?
Was she a monster as well?
-You are not welcome
in my house.
If you can't sleep, drink wine
until you pass
from consciousness.
-Please, think of your boys.
-That is my only remedy.
-What did he mean?
-It does not matter.
That man is a fool.
I don't know
why no one understands me.
My only mission
is to keep us safe.
-Stop you from what?
-Come.
Here.
Look.
They are all there.
You killed all those people.
-Not people. Not souls.
Dead things walking around.
As if they have a right
to our world.
Max, you saw that thing
in the cellar.
It was sick and deceased.
We will set a perimeter.
Nothing or no one
will be allowed to cross it.
We will create
a sterile environment.
Purity of spirit.
And we will begin with those men
from the railroad.
Let the world fall
to the hideous undead and burn.
It will not bother us at all.
We are safe here.
-No.
-No, I'm not going anywhere
with you.
You're insane.
-Insane?
For trying to keep
my family safe?
-There's nothing out there!
I'm not stupid.
And I can see what's happening.
My mother is dead,
because of you.
You were the one
making her sick.
You pulled her away
from everything in her life.
In the end,
she was alone because of you.
We are alone.
-It breaks my heart, Max.
That you think these things
to be true.
But...
at least have a drink
with your father.
Stay then.
-Aah!
-Rudolf, come with me.
-What about Max?
where's Max?
-Come here.
-Ow! Get off me!
-Stop.
Stop!
Help, Max!
Help me!
-Rudy!
- You scared me.
Didn't mean to scare ya.
Tryna take a leak.
Henry?
You alright?
-Now is the time.
Stand up, son.
Stand up.
-End her suffering now
before it even begins.
The way I've shown you.
Strike hard!
Right through the heart.
Be strong! Be bold!
-Do it, son! It is God's will!
Do it! Do it!
It is God's will, son!
Aah!
Aah.
-I'm sorry.
Max.
-I won't let you hurt
anyone else.
-So you finally understand me.
-You're okay.
You're safe now.
You killed him.
He was a monster.
I told you. You're safe now.
-My own father...
had a deep ambivalence
towards me.
I would have cherished
any kind of attention.
Even the harshest criticism.
Anything
but his blatant disinterest.
My grandfather was a peasant who
thought he was an aristocrat.
He had...
no skills to speak of
whatsoever.
Just, uh, an enormous capacity
for selfishness.
I moved through his world
like a little mouse.
And when I left
for medical school...
he barely noticed my absence.
I know that sometimes
I am hard on you.
But you must know that I love
you and your brother very much.
And I will always do
what is best for our family.
I only ask that...
you place your faith in me.